- 各位 - 菲比
- Hi,guys. - Hey,Phoebe.
- 你的约会怎么样? - 不是很好
- How did it go? - Not so good.
他送我到地铁然后跟我说 我们应该再来一次
He walked me home and said,"Let's do this again."
他说要再来一次? 那不是很好吗?
He said,"Let's do this again." That's good,right?
不，"我们应该再来一次"意思是"你将无法再见到裸体的我"
Translated,"Let's do this again" means,"You'll never see me naked."
什么时候这样子的？
Since when?
一直都是这样的啊. 就像是…约会用语
Since always. It's,like,dating language.
比如,“问题不是出在你”代表“就是你”
Like,"It's not you" means,"It is you."
“你真好”意思是说我要和皮革族的酒徒约会…
"You're nice" means,"I'll be dating alcoholics..
然后向你抱怨
and complaining about them to you."
“我们该试试别人”代表
"We should see other people" means:
“我已和别人约会了”
"Ha-ha,I already am!"
大家都懂?
Everybody knows this?
对，善意的谎言
Cushions the blow.
没错，就像父母使小孩的狗安乐死时
Like your parents putting the dog to sleep..
他们会说它跑到别人家农场去住了
and saying it went to a farm.
真有意思,不过我爸妈是真的…
That's funny. Because our parents actually did..
把我们的狗送给别人养了
send our dog off to live on a farm.
罗斯？
Ross?
米纳他们在康乃迪克州的农场
Hello! The Milner's farm in Connecticut?
米纳他们家的农场好棒
The Milners had this unbelievable farm.
有马还有可供追逐的兔子…
They had horses and rabbits to chase.
而且…
And it was..
噢,琪琪
Oh,my God! Chi-Chi!
六人行 第1季 第03集 手指
The One With the Thumb
知道自己不久人世有何感受?
How does it feel knowing you're about to die?
华顿，我的痛苦将在五分钟内消除
Warden,in five minutes my pain will be over.
但你得承受埋葬一个老实人的痛苦
But you'll live with the knowledge that you sent an honest man to die.
表演得真好是吗？
That was really good!
谢了，咱们继续吧
Thanks. Let's keep going.
好，你要我怎么做，迪默?
So,what do you want from me,Dimon? Huh?
我只想回到我的牢房内 因为这样我才可以抽烟
I just wanna go back to my cell,because in my cell I can smoke.
你就在这里抽吧
Smoke away!
我想这就是迪默自己一个在牢房里抽烟的原因
I think this is why Dimon smokes in his cell alone.
- 什么 - 手放轻松
- What? - Relax your hand.
手腕自然点
Let your wrist go.
别太过火!
Not so much!
好的，现在吐口烟
All right. Now take a puff.
就是这样
Right.
- 给我来 - 不，我不能给你烟
- Give it to me. - I'm not giving you a cigarette.
无所谓的，你到底想不想演这个角色?来
It's fine. Do you want to get this part or not? Here.
看着，别把它当成香烟
Now,don't think of it as a cigarette.
把它当成是你想念多时的东西
Think of it as the thing that has been missing from your hand.
夹着它你感到自在
When you hold it,you feel right.
让你感到满足
You feel complete.
- 你很想它? - 没那么严重
- You miss it? - No,not so much.
好吧，抽烟
All right. Now we smoke.
噢,爽呀!
Oh,my God!
- 把它给我 - 不，你有几种选择
- Give me that! - No. You've got options.
你可以像这样抽烟
You can smoke like this:
- 钱德 - 或者只是把它叼在嘴里
- Chandler - Or hold it in your mouth.
把烟给我
Give me the cigarette!
- 你来试试. - 谢谢
- You try. - Thank you.
怎么样？
Okay,how's this?
还不坏
Okay,that's not bad.
好的，当你结束的时候,弹掉它会显得很酷
All right,when you're finished,it's cool if you flick it.
就这样，不断练习
All right,you keep practicing..
我去扑灭着火的沙发
and I'll go put out the sofa.
我认为那东西跟自己脚的大小相等
I thought it was foot size.
不，是和拇指尖到食指尖…
No. It's the distance from the tip of a guy's thumb..
的距离相同的
to the tip of his index finger.
这太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
随便哪个姆指都行?
Can I use either thumb?
我宁可相信脚长理论
I'd rather go with the foot theory.
别告诉我…
All right. Don't tell me.
无咖啡因卡布其诺，是乔伊的
Decaf cappuccino for Joey.
纯咖啡
Coffee,black.
拿铁
Latte.
和冰茶
And an iced tea.
- 我进步神速 - 不错
- I'm getting good at this. - Excellent!
我真行
Good for me!
- 菲比，你没事吧 - 我还好
- You okay,Phoebe? - It's not worth
我的银行
It's my bank.
他们对你怎么了?
- What did they do? - It's nothing
我看我的信件时 看见他们的每月通知
I get my mail and open their monthly "statement."
别激动
Easy!
我的户头多了五百元
And there's $500 extra in my account.
撤旦的奴才又开始活跃了
Satan's minions at work again!
没错，因为我得到银行找他们处理
Now I have to go deal with them
- 别傻了，留着自己用吧 - 这些钱不是我的
- What are you talking about? Keep it! - It's not mine.
我留下来就如同偷窃
If I kept it,I'd be stealing.
如果你拿来花就如同购物
But if you spent it,it would be like shopping.
好吧，就比方说我买了一双很棒的鞋
Say I bought a great pair of shoes.
你们知道我每走一步会听到什么吗?“不是我的…不是我的”
Know what I'd hear with every step? "Not mine. Not mine. Not mine."
即使我再快乐再雀跃都会听到
Even if I was happy and skipping,I'd hear:
“不是我的…不是我的…”
"Not-not mine. Not-not mine."
知道你的意思了
We're with you. We got it.
我无法享受非份之财的乐趣 会有报应的
I'd never be able to enjoy it. It'd be this giant karmic debt.
钱德，你在干什么?
Chandler,what are you doing?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
噢,真恶劣!
Oh,gross!
- 这是什么 - 我在抽烟…
- What is this? - I'm smoking!
你这三年来一直表现良好
You've been so good for three years!
这是我的奖励
And this is my reward.
等等，想想你戒烟后是怎么活过来的
Think about what you went through when you quit.
就算忘了你自己,至少想想我们是怎么过来的
Forget about you. Think about what we went through!
所以这一次我不再戒了
So this time I won't quit.
- 熄掉… - 好吧，我熄掉就是
- Put it out! - I'm putting it out!
噢,不!
Oh,no!
我现在喝不了它了
I can't drink this now.
我要去换衣服了,我有个约会
I'm gonna go. I've got a date.
又是亚伦?进展得如何?
With Alan again? How's it going?
进展的还不错.我们在一起很开心
It's going pretty good. It's nice and we're having fun.
我们何时能见到他?
When do we get to meet him?
今天是星期一…
Let's see,it's Monday..
- 永远别想… - 不要这样嘛
- Never. - Come on!
不,不要再来像史提夫那次的事…
Not after what happened with Steve.
你在说什么?我们都爱史提夫 史提夫很性感
What do you mean? We love Steve. Steve was sexy!
抱歉
Sorry.
我对他有何感觉都不知道 给我一点时间想清楚
I don't know how I feel yet. Let me figure it out.
这么说我们可以见他?
Then can we meet him?
不行
No.
抱歉
Sorry.
乔伊.放过他吧
Joey. Let it go.
我为何要让他们见他?
Why should they meet him?
我带他回去后，他们就像
I bring a guy home and they're like..
就像郊狼一样找畜群中的弱者下手
coyotes picking off the weak members of the herd.
听着，作为一个见了过多坏牛排的人
Listen,as someone who's seen more than her fair share of bad beef..
我告诉你这并不是一件坏事
I'll tell you,that is not such a terrible thing.
你的朋友他们只是关心你
Your friends are just looking after you.
我只希望带一个 他们真正喜欢的男人回家
I wish that once I'd date a guy they liked.
你知道的，他的机会会更渺茫的…
You realize the odds of that happening are slimmer..
- 如果他们根本就没见过这小伙 - 这个我知道
- if they never get to meet the guy. - I know.
- 能让我小声的哭一下吗？ - 哭
- Can't I whimper a little bit? - Whimper.
好了
Okay,I'm done.
罗斯,让它去吧!
Let it go,Ross.
你又不了解琪琪
You didn't know Chi-Chi.
- 你们都保证? - 对，我们保证
- Do you all promise? - We promise.
我们会很友善的
We'll be good.
钱德，你保证会很友善?
Chandler,do you promise to be good?
你可以进来了,但是你的烟屁股朋友得待在外面
You can come in,but your filter-tip buddy stays outside!
亲爱的布菲小姐 谢谢你提醒我们的错误
"Dear Ms. Buffay. Thank you for calling.
我们已将五百元存入你的户头 造成不便之处请多包涵
We've credited you $500. We're sorry for the inconvenience..
请接受此足球电话…
and hope you'll accept this football phone..
做为礼物 你们相信吗？
as our gift." Do you believe it?
现在我多了一千元和一个足球电话
Now I have $ 1000 and a football phone.
这是哪家银行?
What bank is this?
他来了
Okay,it's him.
- 是谁？ - 亚伦
- Who is it? - Alan.
钱德，他来了
Chandler! He's here!
我看起来怎么样？
Do I look okay?
最好再扣上一颗扣子
One more button.
-我是说扣上！扣上怎么样？
Closed! How about closed?
- 我不太清楚 - 好吧
- I didn't know. - Yeah.
拜托，别乱来
Please be good.
记得你们有多么爱我
Remember how much you all like me?
亚伦，这是大家 各位，他是亚伦
Alan,this is everybody. Everybody,this is Alan.
我对各位已如雷灌耳
I've heard so much about all you guys.
谢谢，我明天再打电话给你
I'll call you tomorrow. Thanks.
开始攻击亚伦吧
Let's let the Alan-bashing begin.
谁先开始?
Who's gonna take the first shot?
来呀
Come on!
我来
I'll go.
我们就从他不停剔牙开始
Let's start with how he kept picking
抱歉,我办不到.我们爱他
I'm sorry,I can't do this. We loved him.
我们爱他
We loved him!
等等，我们谈的是我约会的对象吗?
Wait! We're talking about someone I'm going out with?
那个辣椒的小把戏
That pimento trick!
我绝不会再这样看橄榄了
I'll never look at an olive the same way again.
你们都有注意到?
And did you notice?
知道他什么最棒吗? 他的微笑有点邪邪的
Know what was great? His smile was crooked.
对，就像是鞋里的男人 - 什么鞋?
- Yes! Like the man in the shoe! - What shoe?
诗里的
From the rhyme.
有个驼背的人有着扭曲的微笑
There was a man With a crooked smile
他住在鞋子里，有一阵子
Who lived in a shoe For a while
我想亚伦…
So I think Alan..
将成为日后男友被丈量的标准
is the yardstick by which future boyfriends will be measured.
什么日后男友?
Future boyfriends?
- 不，我想他就是了 - 真的呀?
- I think this could be "it." - Really?
他学大卫・哈塞尔霍夫（《海滩游侠》主演）
的样子我就想嫁给他了
I'd marry him for his David Hasselhoff impression alone.
你知道嘛，我也要在派对上这么做
You know I'll be doing that at parties.
- 知道我最喜欢他哪一点? - 哪一点？
- Know what I like most? - What?
他改变我看待自己的方式
The way he makes me feel about myself.
比赛如何?
How was the game?
怎么说呢
Well..
我们赢啦
We won!
太意外了!问题是，这怎么可能呢？
Fantastic! Question. How is that possible?
- 亚伦 - 他真是太不可思议了
- Alan. - He was unbelievable!
他就像兔宝宝一样守每个位置
Like the cartoon where Bugs Bunny plays every position.
但我们有一垒手亚伦、二垒手亚伦…
It was first base,Alan. Second base,Alan..
他使我们形成一个团队
It was like he made us into a team.
对，我们让对手见识到什么叫垒球
We sure showed those Hasidic jewelers a thing or two about softball.
能问你们一个问题吗?
Can I ask a question?
你是否曾感觉亚伦有时…
Do you think Alan is sometimes..
有时怎样?
What?
我说不上来，太亚伦了
I don't know. A little too "Alan"?
不，不可能 你不可能太过于“亚伦”
Oh,no. Not possible. You can never be too "Alan."
没错我们欣赏的是亚伦的内在
It's his innate "Alan-ness" that we adore.
我一个人可以喝下一加仑的亚伦
I,personally,could have a gallon of Alan.
- 嘿,露西 - 嘿,古怪女孩
- Hey,Lizzy. - Hey,weird girl.
- 我带字母汤来给你 - 你挑出有元音的了吗?
- I brought alphabet soup. - Pick out the vowels?
但我把“Y”留下来了 因为Y是半元音
I left in the Y's. Because,"sometimes Y."
- 我还带了其他东西给你 - 咸饼干吗?
- And something else. - Saltines?
但愿你喜欢一千元和足球电话
No,$1000 and a football phone.
什么?
What?
天啊
Oh,my God!
- 这里真的有钱 - 这我知道
- There's really money in here. - I know.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我要给你，我不想要
I want you to have it. I don't want it.
- 不，我得拿东西给你 - 不用了
- I have to give you something. - No,you don't
- 你要我的锡箔纸帽吗? - 不要，因为你需要
- Do you want my tinfoil hat? - No,you need that.
- 不用了，谢谢 - 求你,让我表示我的谢意
- It's okay. Thanks. - Let me do something.
这样吧,你请我喝汽水就扯平了
I'll tell you what. Buy me a soda and we're even. Okay?
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Okay. - Okay.
不用找了
Keep the change.
谢谢你，莉兹
Thanks,Lizzy.
你真的不要椒盐卷饼?
Want a pretzel?
- 不,不用了 - 再见
- No,I'm fine. Thanks. - See you.
一个拇指？
A thumb?
我知道.我打开时它就浮在里面
I know. There it was,just floating..
像个搭便车的
like this tiny little hitchhiker.
或者这是一场竞赛,比如集满五个有奖?
Maybe it's a contest. Like "collect all five."
- 你们想看看吗? - 不用了，谢谢
- Does anyone wanna see? - No,thanks!
别那样，拜托
Don't do that. Come on!
这比姆指还糟糕
It's worse than the thumb.
- 这不公平 - 为何不公平?
- This is so unfair. - Why is it unfair?
我有缺点不行吗?了不起吗？
So I have a flaw! Big deal!
乔伊常扳指关节就不惹人厌?
Joey's knuckle-cracking isn't annoying?
罗斯把每个音发得太清楚
Ross,over-pronouncing every word.
莫妮卡大笑时的鼻音 搞什么嘛
Monica,who snorts when she laughs. I mean,what the hell is that thing?
我接受大家所有的缺点 为何大家就不肯接受我的呢?
I accept those flaws. Why can't you accept me for this?
扳指关节会惹人厌吗?还是只是他比较烦
Does the knuckle-cracking bother everybody,or just him?
没有它我也能活的下去
I could live without it.
觉得有点烦吗? 感觉就和看到菲比咬她的头发时一样?
Is it a little annoying? Or is it like when Phoebe chews her hair?
菲比，别介意 我觉得那样很可爱
Don't listen to him. I think it's endearing.
真的?是吗?
Oh,you do,do you?
咬字清晰又不犯法
There's nothing wrong with speaking correctly.
的确没错
Indeed there isn't.
我该回去工作了
I should get back to work.
那么有人就会拿错他们点的东西了
Otherwise someone might get what they ordered.
头发冒了出来，手套滑落下来 (全都发泄出来了)
The hair comes out and the gloves come off.
你曾和一个你朋友都喜欢的男人约会吗?
Ever go out with a guy your friends really like?
没有
No.
我在和一个我朋友都喜欢的男人约会
I'm going out with a guy my friends really like.
我们在谈郊狼吗?
Are we talking about the coyotes here?
一头牛居然逃脱了
All right! A cow got through.
你能相信吗?
Can you believe it?
就像是，你知道吗…
It's just,you know what?
我毫无感觉
I just don't feel the "thing."
而他们却有感觉.我毫无感觉
They feel the thing. I don't feel it.
你应该要有感觉
Honey,you should always feel the thing.
如果对他没感觉,就把他甩了
If that's how you feel about the guy,dump him.
- 我知道，但很难 - 没错，但他是大人了,他会熬过去的
- It's gonna be really hard. - He'll get over it.
不，他没事.我担心的是其他五人
No,he'll be fine. It's the other five I'm worried about.
- 难道你不尊重你的身体吗? -你难道不明白自己在做什么吗?
- Don't you respect your body? - Don't you see what you're doing?
还有你们的癌症肺气肿和心脏病
I've had it with your cancer,emphysema and heart disease.
至少抽烟很酷,这点你们也很清楚
The bottom line is,smoking is cool,and you know it.
钱德，亚伦找你
Alan wants to speak to you.
真的,他找我?
Really? He does?
老兄，什么事?
Hey,buddy! What's up?
她告诉你了?
She told you about that,huh?
对，我偶尔会犯烟瘾 对，现在
Well,yeah. I have one now and then. Well,yeah,now.
没那么糟
It's not that
这倒是真的
Well,that's true.
天啊，没人这么说过
Gee,you know,no one's ever put it like that before.
好的，谢谢
Well,okay. Thanks.
天啊，他真棒
God,he's good.
- 如果他是个女人,那该有多好 - 是的啊
- If only he were a woman. - Yeah.
小羊排!
Lamb Chop!
那袜子到底有多旧了?
How old is that sock?
如果我手上戴着袜子三十年 它也会开始说话
If I had a sock on my hand for 30 years,it'd be talking too.
有人该换尼古丁贴片了
I think it's time to change somebody's nicotine patch.
- 乔伊在哪儿? - 乔伊吃了我的最后一片口香糖
- Where's Joey? - Joey ate my last stick of gum..
所以我就把他杀了
so I killed him.
你认为这样不对吗?
Do you think that was wrong?
- 我想他在对面 - 谢谢
- I think he's across the hall. - Thanks.
好啦
There you go.
我又重拾快乐的生活
I'm alive with pleasure now.
菲比，你还想吃那个小松饼吗?
Phoebe,do you want the rest of that Pop-Tart?
谁想吃剩下的?
Does anyone want the rest of this Pop-Tart?
我要
Hey,I might.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
汽水公司那些笨蛋 给我七千元当姆指的补偿金
The soda people gave me $7000 for the thumb.
天啊，七千元别闹了 我回家路上又踩到口香糖
And on my way over here I stepped in gum.
这世界到底怎么了?
What is up with the universe?
- 怎么啦？ - 只是觉得大伙儿在一起很温馨
- What's going on? - It's just nice when we're together.
如果大家都有穿内裤会更好
It's nicer when everyone gets to wear underwear.
各位，我有话要说
Please,guys,we have to talk.
等等，我有似曾相识的感觉
Wait! I'm getting a deja vu.
不,好像没有
No,I'm not.
- 好吧,我们需要谈谈. - 瞧,来了
- We have to talk. - There it is!
是有关亚伦的事
Okay,it's about Alan.
关于什么，告诉他我们会去文艺复兴节的
Speaking of which,tell him we're on for the Renaissance Fair.
在此之前，有件事应该让你们知道
Before you get into that,there's something you should know.
真的很难启齿
There's really no easy way to say this.
我决定和亚伦分手
I've decided to break up with Alan.
有第三者?
Is there somebody else?
没有
No,it's just..
只是世事难料，人都会变
you know,things change. People change.
我们没变
We didn't change.
就这样?结束了?
So that's it? It's over?
就这样结束了
Just like that?
放下防御，真心对待一个人…
You let your guard down. You start to care about someone,and..
- 我可以继续伪装… - 可以啊
- I can go on pretending - Okay!
不
No.
这样对我不公平,对亚伦也是 对你们大家也是
That wouldn't be fair to me,Alan,or to you.
是吗?谁要公平?
Well,who wants fair?
我只想要回失去的，回到往日
I just want things back,you know,the way they were.
- 我很抱歉 - 她说抱歉，我舒坦多了
- I'm sorry. - Oh,she's sorry. I feel better.
我真是不敢相信
I can't believe this!
假期就要来临了 我要带他去见我的家人
With the holidays coming up. I wanted him to meet my family.
我会找到新欢的，另一个亚伦
I'll meet someone. There'll be other Alans.
是呀,另一个
Yeah,right!
- 你们不会有事吧? - 我们会好的
- Are you guys gonna be okay? - We'll be fine.
我们只是需要一点时间
We're just gonna need a little time.
我了解
I understand.
我真的很抱歉
- Wow. - I'm really sorry.
我也很抱歉
Yeah,I mean,I'm sorry too.
- 我有点松了一口气 - 松了一口气?
- But I'm a little relieved. - Relieved?
对，我是说我和你在一起很开心
Yeah,well,I mean,I had a great time with you.
只是我受不了你朋友
I just can't stand your friends.
记得我们到中央公园划船吗?
Remember when we went to Central Park and rented boats?
没错，那很有趣
That was fun.
他划得就像维京人一样
He could row like a Viking.
情况如何?
So how'd it go?
你知道的
You know.
他有提到我们吗?
Did he mention us?
他说他会想念你们的
He says he's really gonna miss you guys.
- 悲惨的一天? - 你无法体会
- Rough day,huh? - You have no idea.
过来宝贝
Come here.
- 我受够了，我要抽烟 - 不行…
- That's it. I'm getting cigarettes. - No!
我管不了那么多了,我投降,我是懦夫
I don't care! I'm weak!
我要抽烟
I've gotta have the smoke!
如果你不再抽烟我就给你七千块
If you never smoke again,I'll give you $7000.
好吧,没问题
Yeah,all right.